Guide to the United Hospital Fund of New York records, 1920-1935.
United Hospital Fund of New York records, 1920-1935.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
United Hospital Fund of New York records, 1920-1935.
3003
United Hospital Fund of New York.
.3 cubic ft.
Memorandums, minutes of meetings, letters.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes minutes of meetings, memoranda, correspondence, plans, reports, and financial records of the fund raising organization for New York City hospitals.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes minutes of meetings, memoranda, correspondence, plans, reports, and financial records of the fund raising organization for New York City hospitals.
SUBJECTS
Names:
United Hospital Fund of New York.
Subjects:
Hospitals--Finance.
Places:
New York (N.Y.).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Committee on Dispensary Development
  - Minutes of the Luncheon Meeting on Dispensaries, Jan. 16, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Special Meeting of the Trustees of the United Hospital Fund of New York, Apr. 22, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Memorandum to the Committee by Michael M. Davis Jr. on Aims and Program of Proposed Undertaking, June 7, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of Meeting, June 7, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Sept. 28, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter to the Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. (Exec. Sec.), Oct. 26, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Oct. 26, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter to Edwin R. Embree, Sec. Rockefeller Foundation (enclosed with Memorandum of Nov. 23 ), Nov. 6, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Memorandum to the Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. (including Budget figures for 1921 and related notes), Nov. 23, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of Meeting (and Resolution concerning fund of $500.00), Dec. 2, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Memorandum to the Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. (with enclosure, "Demonstration program...Mount Sinai Hospital" and copy of letter to Dr. Louis I. Dublin, of Metropolitan Life Insurance Company), Dec. 27, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Memorandum to the Sub-Committee on District Dispensary Demonstration from Michael M. Davis, Jr., Dec. 30, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Dec. 30, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of the Meeting on the Sub-Committee on Dist. Disp. Dem., Jan. 7, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum to the Committee, Jan. 24, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Jan. 27, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Copy of Letter to William M. Sloane, Pres. Presbyterian Hospital from John Sherman Hoyt, Jan. 28, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum to the Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr., Dec. 31, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum to the Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr., (A) District Dispensary Demonstration and (B) Proposed Relationship between Committee and Hospital Social Service Association, Feb. 8, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of Special Meeting (and enclosure of memorandum of Feb. 10 from M.M. Davis, Jr.), Feb. 10, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter to John Sherman Hoyt from Robert W. Carle Chairman, Out-Patient Dept. of The Presbyterian Hospital), Feb. 16, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Carbon copy of sheet showing Daily Average of New and Old patients at Cornell University Medical College Dispensary, Jan. 1921, Mar. 10, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Mar. 31, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of Medical Sub-Committee on Dispensary Development, Apr. 14, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Apr. 28, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum from Michael M. Davis, Jr. to Dean of Cornell Medical School re Tentative Plan for a Cooperative Clinic, May 6, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of Meeting, May 26, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Suggested Plan - Development of Health Center Work in New York City, by Anna M. Richardson, June 13, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum to Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. re District Dispensary Demonstaration, June 14, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of Meeting, June 17, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum to Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. re administrator for our Pay Clinic Demonstration at Cornell, July 19, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum to Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. re Report of the Presbyterian Demonstration, Sept. 20, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Sept. 23, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum from Michael M. Davis, Jr. to Committee re meeting of Oct. 28, Oct. 22, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Oct. 28, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Excerpt from the report of Exec. Sec. to the Committee, Oct. 24, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Oct. 31, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memorandum to Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. and propsed Budget for 1922, Nov. 28, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Dec. 2, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Jan. 6, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum to Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. re Committee Meetings, Jan. 21, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum to Committee re Special Meeting on Feb. 9, Feb. 6, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of Special Meeting, Feb. 9, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum for meeting with the Dispensary Development Committee (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum to Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. enclosing Annual Report for Sept. 1920-Jan. 1922, also Report of District Dispensary Demonstration, Feb. 28, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum re meeting of Medical Sub-Committee, Mar. 7, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum of above Meeting which was held Mar. 16, Mar. 17, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum from Exec. Sec. to Committee re Medical Sub-Committee, Mar. 20, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Mar. 24, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum to Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. re training of Dispensary personnel, Apr. 20, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Apr. 28, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum to Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. to Medical Sub-Committee re general aide or assistant, May 18, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Outline of Educational Program (typescript carbon copy), May 23, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of Meeting, May 26, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum to Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr, re Presbyterian Demonstration and Publicity Program, June 20, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of Meeting, June 23, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Sept. 22, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Oct. 26, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter (carbon copy) to Edwin R. Embree, Rockefeller Foundation from Michael M. Davis, Jr., Oct. 28, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Exhibits A, B, and C of Cornell Clinic Attendance, Nov. 1, 1921-Sept. 30, 1922, and financial statement re Cornell Clinic, Oct. 26, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum to Committee from MMD re Policy of Committee's work next year with tentative budget, Nov. 4, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Continuation of above memo, Nov. 6, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Nov. 10, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Dec. 15, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Report on probable reorganization of the Presbyterian O.P.D., Dec. 12, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of Meeting (also outline "Statistical Bureau attached to the Associated Out-Patient Clinics" Jan. 23, 1923 ), Jan. 26, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Feb. 23, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Mar. 23, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Confidential Report to the Committee regarding the Presbyterian Program, Mar. 23, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Apr. 27, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of Meeting (including report on divisions of work, etc.; Pending subjects for research and report; Finances), May 22, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of Meeting, June 26, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Summer Sub-Committees (names of members), June 28, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Sept. 28, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Oct. 26, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Memorandum to Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. re Budget for 1924, Nov. 5, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Nov. 9, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carbon copy of letter from Edwin R. Embree to Mr. Fisher re grant of $145,000 from Rockefeller Foundation, Dec. 6, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Dec. 28, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of Meeting (with carbon copy of Annual Report, Jan. 1, 1923-Dec. 1, 1923), Jan. 25, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Memorandum to Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. re "Unloading Program", Feb. 14, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Feb. 19, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Memorandum to Sub-Committee on the Presbyterian Hosptial re Report on Presbyterian Program, Mar. 3, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Mar. 28, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Apr. 25, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of Meeting, May 23, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Memorandum to Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. re June 24 meeting, June 20, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of Meeting, June 24, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Opinions of the physicians at recent conference regarding committee policy" (typescript initialled MMD), June 30, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Copy of letter from Alfred E. Shipley, M.D. (Chairman Public Health Committee) to Michael M. Davis, Jr., July 3, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Exhibit 'A' of report to Rockefeller Foundation - COMMITTEE ON THE DISPENSARY DEVELOPMENT OF THE UNITED HOSPITAL FUND OF NEW YORK, Report for the year of 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Exhibit 'B' of report to Rockefeller Foundation - "Report to the Committee on Dispensary Development by the Executive Secretary on (1) Status of Work and (2) Future Plans" (21 pp typescript), Sept. 16, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Oct. 2, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of Special Meeting, Oct. 14, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Memorandum from the Rockefeller Committee from the Committee Request for Appropriation for 1925 and Suggestions of Future Program, Oct. 15, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Nov. 19, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Dec. 12, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of Meeting (and Revision of Budget for 1925 ), Jan. 23, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Copy of Letter from Henry J. Fisher to Committee, Feb. 18, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Mar. 27, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter to Executive Committee from Henry J. Fisher etc., Mar. 31, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Apr. 24, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter to Rockefeller Foundation from the Committee (signed by Henry J. Fisher) on future needs; also sheet showing Net Annual Expenditures, 1921-1924 and Budgets, 1925-1926, May 6, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes of Meeting, May 25, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Memorandum to Committee from Michael M. Davis, Jr. re Terminal Program (including 2 charts) - 1) The Clinic Field in New York City, 2) Needs and Activities of the Clinic Field in New York City, Sept. 15, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Sept. 25, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Nov. 5, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes of Meeting (including Tentative Budget for 1926 ), Dec. 18, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Feb. 9, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Apr. 22, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Oct. 5, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Nov. 17, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes of Meeting (including Budget for 1927 ), Feb. 2, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Feb. 10, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes of Meeting, Mar. 24, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes of the Executive Committee, Jan. 30, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes of the first meeting of the Committee in charge, Feb. 24, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes of the committee, Mar. 17, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes of the committee (Special meeting), Apr. 10, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes of the committee, Apr. 21, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes of the committee, May 31, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes of the committee, Dec. 1, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Budget as of June 1, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes of the committee, May 9, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes of the committee, Oct. 19, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes of the committee, Dec. 27, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes of the committee, Feb. 20, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes of the committee, Apr. 2, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes of the committee, June 11, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes of the committee, Nov. 21, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes of the committee (Adv. Comm. on Prob. of Hosp. Adm.), Jan. 21, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes of the committee, Apr. 2, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes of the committee, May 21, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes of the committee, June 23, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes of the committee, Oct. 14, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes of the committee, Jan. 20, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes of the committee, Apr. 29, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes of the committee, June 30, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes of the committee, Nov. 17, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes of the committee (Hosp. Inf. and Service Bureau), Feb. 25, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes of the committee, May 4, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes of the committee, Nov. 2, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes of the committee (Hosp. Inf. and Service Bureau Comm.), Feb. 15, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minutes of the committee, Oct. 31, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minutes of the committee, Feb. 28, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes of the committee, Dec. 13, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes of the committee, May 14, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Minutes of the committee, Jan. 28, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Minutes of the committee, Oct. 14, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Minutes of the committee, Jan. 20, 1932 (also shortened version) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes of the committee, Mar. 24, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes of the committee, May 19, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes of the committee, Nov. 2, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes of the committee, Dec. 21, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes of the committee, Feb. 8, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes of the committee, May 25, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes of the committee, Oct. 17, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes of the committee, Feb. 9, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Minutes of the committee, Apr. 5, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Minutes of the committee, June 5, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Minutes of the committee, Nov. 2, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Minutes of committee, Feb. 28, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Minutes of committee, May 9, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Printed Material
  - The Hospital Survey for New York, Vol. I, by Haven Emerson, M.D. United Hosptial Fund, NY., 1937 (Box 2)
  - Health and Employment, by Lucille Spellman. Thesis, University of Minnesota., 1938 (Box 2)
  - Two Studies of the Social Aspects of Health Problems of Public Relief Clients. Committee of Medical Care in Community Health of The American Association of Medical Social Workers., 1935 (Box 2)
  - A Tradition of Service. United Hospital Fund of New York., ca. 1961 (Box 2)
  - The Use of Convelescent Care Facilities. United Hospital Fund of New York., 1948 (Box 2)
  - The Background to Current Thinking and Problems in Convelescent Care, by Lester Peddy., 1948 (Box 2)
  - The Effects of Separation on Children Treated for Asthma by Samuel Kaminsky., 1948 (Box 2)